<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Colin Riddell</title>
    <link>https://colin-riddell.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Colin Riddell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 19:04:15 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://colin-riddell.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Stack Curry #1: The Problem</title>
      <link>https://colin-riddell.github.io/post/full-stack-curry-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 19:04:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://colin-riddell.github.io/post/full-stack-curry-part-1/</guid>
      <description>This is part 1 in a series of posts. In this series I am going to explain how I created a full-stack curry ordering app&amp;rsquo;. Yes, you heard that correctly. I built and deployed into production a curry ordering app that allows people to order curry online. The project was inspired by the lovely team over at #hardeepisyourcurry
I&amp;rsquo;m going to share how I did it in as much detail as possible, while highlighting the learning curves and problems that I faced along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharing dependencies between Spring Boot Microservices with Maven</title>
      <link>https://colin-riddell.github.io/post/sharing-dependencies-between-microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 11:29:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://colin-riddell.github.io/post/sharing-dependencies-between-microservices/</guid>
      <description>Sharing dependencies between Spring Boot Microservices and projects with Maven for better code-reuse and clean design
What&amp;rsquo;s the problem You&amp;rsquo;re looking at microservices, but you realise you want to send an object from one service to the other. You write a class, and then you copy and paste it from the code of one service to the other &amp;hellip; 💡 there must be a better way to do this. You&amp;rsquo;re a good engineer and you know that copying around this POJO is bad practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting With Scala</title>
      <link>https://colin-riddell.github.io/post/starting-with-scala/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 21:52:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://colin-riddell.github.io/post/starting-with-scala/</guid>
      <description>Scala is a functional programming language.
For years, I&amp;rsquo;ve always shied away from functional programming languages. I&amp;rsquo;ve done that because I always thought they were only really used by hard-core academic computer scientists to make themselves sound intelligent in front of others.
I&amp;rsquo;ve found out recently there are some really fun and powerful things to be learned from functional languages, such as Scala. They&amp;rsquo;re fast, good for asynchronous operations, have low latency and because of that they are becoming more prevalent and sought after to meet the real-time, low-latency demands of today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying to Cloud with DigitalOcean &#43; Docker</title>
      <link>https://colin-riddell.github.io/post/docker-intro-with-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 18:19:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://colin-riddell.github.io/post/docker-intro-with-do/</guid>
      <description>Containerization allows development teams to move fast, deploy software efficiently, and operate at an unprecedented scale.
 They are small They are fast They consume no more engergy than running an application They take up 100&amp;rsquo;s of times less space and memory than virtual machines  Setup Optional Get a DO account https://m.do.co/c/e224d565e5ec - this link gives 100 USD credit.
Install Docker - do before starting Docker Download - Mac</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>